Molly Moran

Educator

CONTACT



744 Oak Leaf Bluff Drive



636-229-2930



mollymoran11@yahoo.com

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science/ Elementary 1-6

University of Missouri

Certification

Elementary 1-6

PROFILE

I am currently a third grade teacher in the Hazelwood School District at Barrington Elementary. During the last three years I have planned out lessons with teammates, attended Professional Developments and PLC's, learned how to work with the Deaf and Hard and Hearing students in my room, and so much more. This year I have modified and differentiated lessons when needed and used data to understand how I can set student goals. A part of this year that I feel I have improved on is my classroom approach and flexibility. By building relationships and trying different strategies, I believe that I made a classroom environment where students supported each other and increased their effort throughout the year.

EXPERIENCE

Third Grade Teacher/Second Grade Teacher

Hazelwood School District, Barrington Elementary | 2019 - Present

- Built classroom community using morning meetings to allow students to share thoughts and ideas.
- Attended Professional Developments throughout the year consisting of becoming trauma informed and aware of student mental health.
- Cooperated with grade level teammates to have consistent plans and learn new approaches in teaching through PLC and team meetings.
- Applied classroom management techniques based on student needs and abilities such as conscious discipline and PBIS strategies.
- Presented curriculum in multiple ways such as gradual release, small groups, or partner work.
- Applied the Investigations math program and MySci science program in my
- Incorporated technology skills to assess students during virtual learning.

Third Grade Teacher

Hazelwood School District, Brown Elementary | 2018 - 2019

- Built relationships with each student and encouraged a growth mindset.
- Attended PLC's and Professional Developments throughout the year involving setting/reflecting data goals and de-escalation strategies.
- Cooperated with grade level teammates to have consistent plans and learn new approaches in teaching.
- Applied classroom management techniques based on student needs and abilities.
- Learned about the needs of DHH (Deaf or Hard of Hearing) students including paraprofessionals and interpreters.
- Presented curriculum in multiple ways such as gradual release, small groups, or partner work.
- Applied the Investigations math program and MySci science program in my classroom.

Professional Development

HAZELWOOD-2020

Trauma Informed

Mental Health Awareness

Technology Usage

PBIS During Virtual Learning

HAZELWOOD-2019

Trauma Informed
Guided Reading Groups
PLTW Training
PBIS School Environment

HAZELWOOD-2018

De-escalation Strategies Gradual Release Guided Reading Groups Investigations Training

PEERS-2018

Putting Your Best Foot Forward: Advice from HR Verbal De-escalation Strategies

PEERS-2017

Smart Board and Smart Notebook Training

EXPERIENCE (CONTINUED)

Teacher Assistant

Parkway School District, Barretts and Carmen Trails | 2017 - 2018

- Taught subject lessons and facilitated student experiments
- Observed grade levels k-5 during first semester to learn different teaching styles and look at different grade level content
- Participated in planning times with host teacher for lesson plans and ideas for personal growth as a teacher
- Planned lessons using Envisions math and Lucy Calkins writing
- Attended staff meetings and district wide professional developments
- Conducted various lessons while co-teaching alongside host teacher
- Worked with small groups and kept records of student improvement

Student Teaching/ SYOSP Program (Continued)

Columbia Public Schools, Mill Creek Elementary | 2016 - 2017

- Taught subject lessons and facilitated student experiments
- Observed grade levels k-5 during first semester to learn different teaching styles and look at different grade level content
- Participated in planning times with host teacher for lesson plans and ideas for personal growth as a teacher
- Planned lessons using Envisions math and Lucy Calkins writing
- Attended staff meetings and district wide professional developments
- Conducted various lessons while co-teaching alongside host teacher
- Worked with small groups and kept records of student improvement
- Met with university supervisor to discuss improvements made throughout semester and review lesson plans
- Discussed personal growth made throughout student teaching with cooperating teacher
- Participated in events outside of school setting with students and staff

REFERENCES

Jenna Busch Instructional Coach, Hazelwood

314-953-4477 jhawkins@hazelwoodschools.org

Hayley Wojciechowski Teacher, Hazelwood

314-740-5520 hwojciechowski@hazelwoodschools.org

Tyrone McNichols Former Principal, Barrington Elementary

tyronemcnichols@gmail.com